Gabriela Suárez Carvajal

Computer and Systems Engineer. Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Frontend developer Edad: 27 años

Location: Bogotá, Colombia

Linkeln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabrielasuárez/

Summary

Gabriela is a strong work ethic engineer with a degree in Computer and Systems engineering and 3 years of broad experience in the technology world. Since then She has worked for companies such as Instaleap, a global last mile start-up, and Quick developing a web application. She has learned the importance of moving fast and sustainably to stay in business while creating quality code.

Formal Education

 Universidad Nacional de Colombia. Bogotá. Colombia Computer and systems engineering. 2014-2019

Additional Education

Advanced English – 256 hours – Universidad Nacional de Colombia – 2015

Experience

Instaleap - Bogotá - Colombia Front-End Developer / 2019-2023

From the outset of the frontend development process, I have been involved in every step of the way, starting with collaborating with stakeholders to plan and strategize, creating technical designs, consuming API data, writing code, transforming designs from Figma into flawless HTML/CSS, and deploying. I've been here from scratch, from the initial development stage to the point where we switched to a minimum viable product (MVP), and from then until now, when the product is being used by 130,000 to 170,000 people every day with clients such as Wallmart, and Oxxo. My team and I focus on maintaining existing features, seeking out opportunities for enhancements in the code, and continuously expanding our knowledge. In order to promote collaborative teamwork, we employ the use of SCRUM methodology and implement various collaborative practices such as conducting meetings, engaging in peer programming, and performing code reviews.

E-commerce

This is a web page that enables you to place market orders from the comfort of your own home.

Call-Center

This is an app that enables you to place orders for groceries making a call.

Technologies used: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, React Context, Jest, Git, Storybook, Yalc, AWS, Cypress, Apollo GraphQL, HTML, CSS, React Router.

Quick - Bogotá - Colombia Front-End Developer | 2019

I participated in the frontend development process from planning, to technical design, coding, deployment and collaborate with other developers in the engineering team to develop new features.

Quick App

Application that allows you to request one of the following services:

- A vehicle to deliver shipments or correspondence.
- A vehicle to transport, store and distribute cargo.
- A worker to clean a house or office.

Accelerator

This application is intended for individuals who are in charge of managing workers responsible for carrying out requested services. Its main function is to allow them to oversee the progress of the service, keep track of the workers' activities, and communicate with the customer.

Mv Account

This application permits the user to view and modify their services, payment methods, preferred addresses, and preferred routes.

Technologies used: React, JavaScript, Redux, HTML, CSS React Router, Redux Saga.

Woombat Consulting Group. Bogotá. Colombia. *Junior Consultant | 2018*

I worked for a company that manages multiple projects simultaneously, and my duties included contributing to the development of several projects, comprehending the requirements of stakeholders, writing code, and continuously presenting the product to the client for feedback and improvement.

EagleView

An application that provides a user interface that manages connections with different databases and then automatically loads them into Cloudera.

Technologies used: Django and PySpark.

Object Analizer

User interface for a IA with three main functionalities: analyze the content of given images, convert audios into text and extract text from an image.

Technologies used: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and React Context.

Procesos y Operaciones. Bogotá. Colombia. *Consultor Junior | 2017*

At this company, my main responsibilities were to gain insight into the client Previsora, and then take charge of the frontend development process, which encompassed stages from initial planning to technical design and coding.

Single Registration

Web application to enter, filter and download legal records.

Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Ruby on Rails.

Universidad Nacional de Colombia *Student | 2014-2019*

PC-UN

This is a web-based application that enables users to verify the locations of post-consumer waste collection points.

Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Ruby on Rails.

UN-Trueque

Web and mobile applications for the exchange of goods or services.

Technologies used: JavaScript, Android, HTML, CSS and Ruby on Rails.

Skills

Programming Languages:

- React 4 years
- JavaScript 4 years
- TypeScript 6 months
- Jest 6 months
- Ant Design 3 years
- React Context 3 years
- HTML 4 years
- CSS 4 years
- Redux 5 months
- Redux Saga 3 months
- React Router 2 months

Development Tools:

- Jira 3 years
- o Git 4 years

Software programs:

Visual Studio Code 4 years

Agile methodologies:

o SCRUM 3 year

Languages:

• English: Intermediate

o Spanish: maternal language

Courses

- CSS grid layout
- Javascript basics
- Online web development
- Unit testing with jest in react
- Responsive design